All right, so now
I'm going to show
you how to turn
all of these patterns
you've just come up
with from outliers into
video ideas and a
strategy. Most important thing
to mention here, though,
is that you will
fail if you make
videos that are not
based on these patterns.
Like I said in
the last video, don't
just come up with
ideas and be like,
I'm going to try
that. It is not
going to work. But
also keep this in
mind. So if you
are a existing channel,
you've got an existing
following, if you do
this and then you
start making videos that
are like wildly different
from what your viewers
expect from you, you're
going to get less
views. So keep that
in mind, too. If
we're experienced, we want
to be doing this.
So I'm going to
use this image again.
All the colored ones
are me just repeating
what works. The ones
in between, so this
one and this one,
were crap for views
and sales. They just
didn't work, right? All
of these other ones,
they've got varying views,
but they either grew
the business a ton
or got a ton
of views. So as
far as I'm concerned,
they're all outliers. It's
literally me just repeating
what worked. So what
I try and do.
Is every three or
four videos, I try
the new thing, knowing
it's probably not going
to work, but then
I just keep playing
it safe, repeating what
works over and over
again. So don't necessarily
feel like you need
to reinvent the wheel.
Every video you make,
you don't. All right.
So I'm going to
show you how to
come up with a
title. So the first
thing we do is
we go to our
patent bank. And what
you're going to have
is you're going to
have your channels data.
You're going to have
people from your niches,
adjacent niches. All you
need to do is
come up with one
title from this data.
So. So I'm going
to say, look, I'm
going to try something
slightly different. But this
title here, I really
like drumming mistakes that
kill your progress. I
did them all. Nine
hundred thousand views. It's
also in line with
the things that we
know our viewers like.
Right. So the viewers
based on our own
channel, who to meet,
she's kind of love
mistakes. So I feel
pretty safe and another
mistakes video being worth
a shot. And I
think this is kind
of an interesting title.
So I'm going to
say, all right, let's
pick this. Then I'm
going to adjust it.
So. So I'm going
to turn it to
just drawing mistakes that
kill your hand speed
that I did them
all. I'm not sure
I might put that
in. I don't know
yet if that's actually
helpful. I feel like
this is good because
we know that in
Dimitri's channel, hand speed
was the thing they
cared about. Right. So
they love fast. They
loved speed. So they
don't want to lose
that. So I feel
pretty confident saying mistakes
that kill the house
speed. It's a format
viewers like, which is
a mistakes video listicle.
And it's about the
thing they really care
about. So this feels
like a good video.
It is. For me.
And then what we're
going to do is
just going to run
it through the title
checklist. So the title
checklist is basically going
to make sure it's
not too long. It's
not confusing. They use
power words. And as
you can see, it
takes off pretty much
everything on that list.
So happy days. Then
I'm going to do
is I'm going to
ask guardrails for feedback.
Now, I don't have
Dimitri's guardrails up here,
but all you would
do is you would
put this in and
say, is this a
good idea? .
So awesome. So I've
got a little egg
embrace up here and
I'm going to move
this first thing. And
I'm just going to
be showing myself a
brought a little Virgin
Access Play. So listen,
we're going to play
a third one in
a row. What's the
time certain here for
him that seems just
about, like 4 omuj
bottle com not doing
it's my best guess
because he's going to
take it. NBD Let's
pull that. Right. anything
that we might have
missed. And then we're
gonna use a human,
a real life human
for feedback too, so
long as you have
that package. And all
that means is you
go to Discord, go
to packaging feedback, new
post, put your title
in here, can I
get feedback on this
title? But just keep
in mind, if you're
an experienced channel and
you already have outliers,
then we're just gonna
look at your channel
to make sure they're
in line with your
channel first. That's why
it's important you put
your URL in your
description here so that
we can actually click
on it. I haven't
done it, naughty Ed.
So that's it, the
first step is just
a title for a
video. And then what
we do is we
come up with three
thumbnails for each title.
Now, you're gonna be
going, what the, three?
And you're gonna hate
me. But let me
show you why this
is one of the
biggest time -saving things
you're ever gonna do
on YouTube and one
of the most important,
because YouTube now gives
us the split tester.
So if I go
over to my YouTube
studio,
every video I make,
we can load three
thumbnails in. And what
that means is we
can learn three times
faster. So let's say
we put out one
video and a yellow
video is a lesson
learned. This column on
the left, they listened
to what I told
them to do and
they put in three
thumbnails. And it was
very clear that one
thumbnail style won by
a mile. So we
go, ah, we'll take
that lesson into our
next video. This person
ignored me and went,
now I'm just gonna
do one thumbnail per
video. And it meant
they had to post
three videos until they
learned that same lesson.
Now you might be
thinking, I'm still gonna
do it, but well,
after nine weeks, this
is how many lessons
we can learn my
way. And then this
is how much time
you waste if you
do it the other
way. But even more
terrifying, if you ignored
me for three years,
which many of you
will, but you're gonna
do it again,
you're gonna do it
again, Posting one video
a week, we could
learn 52 lessons over
the course of the
year, making three thumbnails.
Making one, it will
take us three years
to learn the same
amount of lessons. You
will waste two years
if you ignore me.
So look, it's up
to you. You probably
have a brain and
you probably have quite
an intelligent brain seeing
as you could afford
this program.
Take this seriously. But
look, it doesn't have
to be that much
work. Now to start,
if you're new and
small, it's gonna hurt
this, like making three
thumbnails is a lot,
but the time savings
are massive. So the
way we do it
is like this. We're
gonna put three different
strategies for each title.
So remember there was
like six or seven
strategies I showed you.
So let's say the
title is this one,
exactly how to create
a million dollar YouTube
strategy. The first strategy
I always use is
cognitive dissonance. So cognitive
dissonance, if you remember,
is basically telling people
not to do something,
something they thought they
should be doing in
its simplest form. We
kind of challenge what
they thought to be
true. So people like
to use SEO to
grow their YouTube channels.
I always tell them
not to, so that
would get their attention.
Then I've tried a
result based one. The
result here is simply
just putting a million
dollar channel in the
thumbnail and that's kind
of it. And then
this is a comparison
one. Could still maybe
class it as a
result because it's got
before and after and
it's showing zero to
a million, that's it.
So the process is
this. We research patterns,
we make a title,
we make three thumbnails
for it, and then
YouTube will give you
some data. Now I'm
not gonna go into
details of how this
works right now. We'll
do it later in
the measurement and launching
module. And then we
set the winner. And
then if we learn
a lesson, we can
then take that lesson
into the next video
and grow. So what
you're gonna do for
creating a thumbnail is
this. So the first
things first is don't
just go and make
like a really polished
thumbnail. All I would
do is this. So
we've got this title
that we're gonna take,
drawing mistakes that kill
your hand speed. Now
we need to come
up with some concepts.
And we know that
from the thumbnails that
works already, just play
this as text did
really well. We know
that curiosity thumbnails did
well, results thumbnails and
social hacking thumbnails did
well. So I'm just
gonna try a curiosity
result and a social
hack based on the
data I found of
what's doing well. And
then we've got still
this, stop this, do
this. So I might
just use some of
this text again cause
it's already worked. So
Dimitri's channel is, if
we look at his
outliers, it's always drums
being shown. We don't
need to try and
reinvent the wheel. Let's
just keep it simple,
right? I like this
one, big drum here.
Stop this, it's a
mistakes one. So I'm
probably gonna take this
other guy's title, which
we've adjusted and make
it look more like
a genuine Dimitri. So
we might turn around
and go, right, let's
doodle the drum being
played. And what I'm
gonna do is I'm
gonna imagine that there's
a big drum here
and there's some sticks
here. And there's some
hands here. Now drums
are a lot harder
to draw than just
a person's face. And
then we would have
stopped this. Like, do
you know what? I'm
gonna put on two
lines cause that's gonna
fill the gap a
bit better. What are
we gonna do here?
Hopefully you guys can
see a thumbnail mistake.
Got this horrid big
line in the middle.
So I'm gonna reduce
that line. And then
what we got here
is, why is that
all wonky? Anyway, a
little arrow and some
of these dots. Remember
I showed you the
dots, how they work.
So I might turn
around and go, right,
we're gonna bring in
some of Dimitri's dots.
And it's gonna be
very, very draft, but
we don't need anything
more than very draft.
Like this doesn't need
to be a masterpiece.
So that's one draft.
And then I'd go,
right, this is the
curiosity. Stop what? Now
I need a result
one, because that was
the other strategy we
thought we'd try based
on what had worked.
So I'm gonna go
to, I'm gonna look
at Dimitri's own channel
cause he's got lots
of cool stuff on
here. I don't think
I need to go
to the competition. And
I'm gonna say, I
like just play this.
Oh no, do you
know what people liked
in his is they
like speed. So I'm
gonna do something like
faster hands in one
week. I might try
something as simple as
drum from the top
down like this. So
I'm gonna do another
little doodle. It's gonna
be another amazing work
of art.
It's gonna be something
as simple as like
drum stick. All right,
just pretend that there's
a good sticks here.
Some hands coming in,
holding the sticks. This
looks weird. And then
what I'm gonna have
is play. I'm gonna
make five X big.
Remember text boxing, where
we make the lines
kind of as big.
And then we're gonna
go faster.
Look at this, what
a work of art
we have. All right.
So I'm not gonna
worry if things overlap
right now, or there's
like dodgy design mistakes,
like having the text
too close to the
side. That's all we
want. We've got the
second one, rough design.
Okay, and then the
next one I would
have as like a
social hack and just
to save you some
mucking around. This is
what I made earlier.
This is supposed to
represent Dave Grohl.
So this is Dave
Grohl playing the drums
and it would be
a good photo of
him. And then we'd
have stopped this with
like an arrow pointing
at him. So we'd
probably go on Google
and find an image
of him playing the
drums and then just
have stopped doing this.
And I came up
with this art because
we've got here, look,
his outlier, Phil Collins,
right? And maybe we
could bring in some
drum music and mistake,
but this one here,
I think I'm just
gonna keep it simple.
So then the next
thing I want you
to do is to
go to this website,
it's called thumbsup .tv.
Put in the title
and then whack in
your image. And it's
gonna show this YouTube
looking thing. Then we're
gonna screenshot it and
we're gonna dump it
onto a vision board.
Now I use some
software called Milanote. You
really don't have to
use that. You can
access this if you
don't want. Like I
think I paid for
it. I don't actually
know. Got some good
accounting skills there. And
then we're gonna do
that with all of
them. So some others
playing a drum there.
And then we're gonna
go to this one.
Same thing. Stop this.
Okay, I'm gonna wipe
that in. So we've
now got this little
vision board where we
got a rough idea
of what's going on.
And I like to
put the outlier. These
have been based on
two. So I might
screenshot one of the,
outliers here. Just have
this on the vision
board too. So that
you can see where
all the pieces of
the puzzle are come
from. Then what you're
gonna do is just
line it up like
this.
And just screenshot the
whole thing. So then
for those of you
on the support package,
they then just go
back to the feedback,
type in the title,
new post. And then
you're just gonna drop
in that image. And
you're gonna say, can
I get some feedback?
And then we're gonna
post it. And you
just wait for us
guys to come in
and give you feedback.
Now, what we're gonna
do is we know
that these are doodles.
Okay? So we're not
gonna turn around and
go, oh, this looks
awful. We're just looking
at this. Is the
strategy good? Is it
nice and simple? Is
the copy interesting? Does
it work with this
sort of title? And
it's also super helpful
if you do put
the outliers that made
it up. Because what
a lot of people
do is they ignore
everything I've taught them
to do. Even though
they've paid a lot
of money to listen
to me, tell them
what to do. And
they're like, they just
come up with their
own ideas. And me
and the team know,
we've been doing YouTube
for years. So I
can see when an
idea is not based
on an outlier cause
I know millions of
outliers.
So to save us
from going, is this
based on an outlier?
Which is basically us
saying, we think you've
made this up, go
back and do this
properly. Put this here
to stop us asking
it now.
Or put these here
so we can make
sure you actually based
on outlier. Cause sometimes
people don't realize that
they've misunderstood outliers. So
it's helpful if you
have this. Once you've
been using the system
a while and you've
got used to the
feedback, you can probably
start to drop that
out because you'll have
stopped ignoring what I
tell you to do.
And that's it. So
we might give you
a bit of feedback
and say, look, drumming
mistakes that kill your
hand speed, play five
times faster. That's positive.
This title is negative.
Maybe we should have
a negative and a
negative rather than a
positive negative. So stop
playing power diddles, something
like that. But that
will depend on the
content. So once you've
done this, you then
go and make the
designs. And then what
I'd recommend doing is
you can just drop
these images into the
thumbnail bot. Now I
haven't got the thumbnail
bot in front of
me inside the YouTube
coach, but it looks
something like this or
will look like this.
You will put in
a title of your
video and then you'll
just drop in the
image. And it's gonna
do a quick check
to make sure you're
not making any of
the design mistakes people
do like overcrowdedness. Now
keep in mind, this
is not perfect. It's
just a very fast
way of doing a
design check. And then
I'd recommend you come
and you drop again.
I know it's a
pain in the butt,
but you drop again
your thumbnails into the
feedback room like Stefan
has done here amazingly.
Now I used to
get everyone to make
nine thumbnails like this
which is actually optimum
because then we can
look at different text
examples and stuff. But
so many people complained.
I got it back
to three. If you
wanna do it nine
like this, right? You
basically have three different
photos and then three
different texts for each
photo and we'll help
pick the top three.
But I cut it
back to three because
I listened to your
guys' feedback. All right.
So once you've done
that, you've got a
thumbnail and a title,
that's your idea. And
I'll teach you how
to use the split
tester later,
but that's it. And
then you just repeat
this. So really you
wanna batch the ideation
and come up with
three to four thumbnails
and titles at once
for different videos. Because
what that mean is
you can drop it
into our feedback. We
can give you feedback
on all of them
in one go. It
will be much quicker
for you to produce
them too. But before
I move on, just
wanna show you a
problem that you're gonna
come up against when
you're doing this. So
let's say we are
researching this channel. So
this is a channel
called Theory of One
that's growing really quick.
This lady's great. And
you can see she's
got some videos down
here with 200 ,000
views, 200 ,000 views.
Like she's smashing it
as a new channel.
20 ,000 views, 48
,000 views. That one
went off and did
amazing things very fast.
So let's say she's
in our niche or
an adjacent nation. We're
like, oh yeah, cool.
I'm gonna take some
of her patterns and
ideate from this channel.
So if we break
down what her viewers
want, there's this title
structure she uses. The
X will make you
Y. And you can
see the rule of
opposites will make people
obsessive view. The cognitive
bias will give you
cult like fans. The
enemy effect will make
you magnetic.
So she's using very
cool content. She's using
very curiosity driven language.
She's got social proof
in here, like pop
culture sort of stuff
as well. Social hacking,
sorry.
And we might then
turn around and go,
right, I'm gonna take
all of these things
and apply them to
my channel. So I
ideate a video that
looks like this. I've
got the X will
make you Y title
going on down here.
I've got some psychological
principles in there. I've
got some curiosity driven
language. I'm using The
Rock and Taylor Swift.
Who's not gonna click
on that? Well, let
me tell you something.
This video would flop
harder than turning it
off. I'm turning off
the air supply to
one of those inflatable
tube men you see
outside of car garages
in America. Because look
at my channel. Like
I built the thing
on clear strategic promises
in my titles and
thumbnails and like authority
back phrasing and clear
end results and saying
I'm gonna build a
system. I did not
build my channel on
psychological principles to get
specific results. I don't
know anything about that.
I can barely say
it. I also don't
use celebrities because I
don't think you guys
care about The Rock
or Taylor Swift. And
I'm never gonna teach
people about the rule
of attraction because I
don't have a clue
what that is. So
this lady is blowing
up and what's gonna
happen on your journey
is you're gonna come
across all this data
and you're gonna ideate
from it and you're
gonna have big flops
because you won't have
necessarily established exactly what
your viewers want yet
or you'll leave what
they want and try
something new and it'll
flop. So the name
of the game here
really is realizing that
just cause it worked
for one channel doesn't
mean it will definitely
work for us. And
the only way we're
actually gonna be able
to discover this is
of course, with the,
you know, with the
annoying graph map thingy
I keep showing you
where we come up
with ideas, we test
it, we measure it,
we adjust, and then
we repeat what works.
So only what works
is left and grows
our channel. So what
you wanna do is
research patterns, test, keep
works and don't just
blindly copy unrelated patterns
and expect identical results
cause it just doesn't
work like that. So
as I mentioned, ongoing,
you're gonna batch three
to four videos at
once and then you
repeat what works. And
what we really wanna
end up with is
like three tried and
tested formats. You keep
repeating. So that's all
you need to do
right now. Next, we're
gonna move on to
planning the content. I'm
gonna teach you how
to plan and then
we're gonna plan this
video together.